historyofmassachusetts.org 2018-12-15

# Privacy Policy - History of Massachusetts Blog

Privacy Policy

We take your privacy seriously. This policy describes what personal information we collect and how we use it. (This privacy policy is applicable to websites falling under the primary holder HistoryofMassachusetts.org)

Routine Information Collection

All web servers track basic information about their visitors. This information includes, but is not limited to, IP addresses, browser details, time stamps and referring pages. None of this information can personally identify specific visitors to this site. The information is tracked for routine administration and maintenance purposes, and lets me know what pages and information are useful and helpful to visitors.

Cookies and Web Beacons

Where necessary, this site uses cookies to store information about a visitor’s preferences and history in order to better serve the visitor and/or present the visitor with customized content.

Advertising partners and other third parties may also use cookies, scripts and/or web beacons to track visitors to our site in order to display advertisements and other useful information. Such tracking is done directly by the third parties through their own servers and is subject to their own privacy policies.

Controlling Your Privacy

Note that you can change your browser settings to disable cookies if you have privacy concerns. Disabling cookies for all sites is not recommended as it may interfere with your use of some sites. The best option is to disable or enable cookies on a per-site basis. Consult your browser documentation for instructions on how to block cookies and other tracking mechanisms.

Use of Personal Information

We use personal information to allow us to process your service requests, send out newsletters, personalize your visit to our websites, personalize your use of our products, and enable us to improve the products and services we offer. We may occasionally carry out market research and send you details of services and offers that we think may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive such information, please e-mail historyofmassaachusetts@gmail.com, or, alternatively, when we send you an e-mail, it will contain a provision for you to opt out of receiving any further information from us.

Special Note About Google Advertising and/or Mediavine Advertising

Any advertisements served by Mediavine and/or Google, Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These cookies allow Mediavine and/or Google to display ads based on your visits to this site and other sites that use Mediavine and/or Google advertising services. Learn how to opt out of Mediavine and/or Google’s cookie usage. As mentioned above, any tracking done by Google through cookies and other mechanisms is subject to Google’s own privacy policies.

About Google advertising: What is the DoubleClick DART cookie? The DoubleClick DART cookie is used by Google in the ads served on publisher websites displaying AdSense for content ads. When users visit an AdSense publisher’s website and either view or click on an ad, a cookie may be dropped on that end user’s browser. The data gathered from these cookies will be used to help AdSense publishers better serve and manage the ads on their site(s) and across the web. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy.](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

About Google Analytics: Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google. Google utilizes the data collected to track and examine the use of www.historyofmassachusetts.org, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google also uses advertising cookies to identify the age, gender and interests of visitors to www.historyofmassachusetts.org. Google may use the data collected to build reports and remarketing lists which will be used to help AdSense publishers better serve and manage the ads on their site(s) and across the web. Google and third-party vendors also use cookies to serve ads based on visitor’s past visits to www.historyofmassachusetts.org. To opt-out of the use of Google analytics cookies, you may install Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

A Special Note About Affiliate Marketing

HistoryofMassachusetts.org is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

HistoryofMassachusetts.org is also a participant in various other affiliate programs designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees and commissions by linking to them.

Contact Information

Concerns or questions about this privacy policy can be directed to historyofmassachusetts@gmail.com for further clarification.
